hi there this is my new sound drum that
i've made
for making
films and
moving over to podcasts
this is a promotional film so if you
want to switch off and you don't want to
hear
a promotional film then
i'm warning you in advance
a little bit about background history
i've had from 1980 to 2014
my own i've run my own personal dojos
and what they've
been all owned by me
before that it was a sports halls
and uh next year will be my 50 years in
nike day
so for 34 of them
i i ran my own dojos
i found that um it was really exciting
for me because you could watch different
students
they would come to regular classes and
apart from friday nights i think i was
basically training or teaching every
day of the week
over those years
um in those days
i kid i was not only with me but
very vibrant it's never been
a massive art like karate
and
judo
it's been more of a niche
uh martial art
but
what i found was i used to have
uchidashi come from all over the world
means living student if you don't know
and it was quite exciting they would
come
males females
of all ages
they would come they would book up for a
period of time sometimes months and
months
um
perhaps
even
a year or two
depending on what
what their finances were and also we
would allow them to work after they'd
been there a short period we would allow
them to go and work to
subsidize their training and also have
money to live
i found it's very encouraging because a
human being would walk in
and meet me
and
we would start by giving them a program
and perhaps
the first thing would be apart from
a few weapons they would have to train
every day
i would teach them what i wanted them to
do obviously and then they would
carry on and each day they had to do for
a minimum of one hour
um that own personal training sometime
within the day
and i would teach a morning class for
one hour and an evening class for
perhaps an hour and a half what would be
a regular class
and then the yucci dashi would have to
do
an hour of some time the day of a set
piece and i remember that the set piece
partly was they had to do a forward
who chemist forward and backward and
chemist left and right hand side
and the and it had to be
the first month was
the challenge of doing 25
forward rolls left and right without
stopping so they would go across the
tammy back turn
across the tummy turn turn turn so it
was continuous and when they got to 25
they could stop
i would check them and watch their
progress and once i was happy with their
body shapes
and what they were
achieving
i would increase in
segments
how many chemists they would have to do
or how many techniques
but sticking with the ukemi side
i remember
i said to
one of the dashes okay i'm pleased with
your
advancement on new cameos
i'm going to set you a challenge because
you're with me for four months
and uh it may have been longer now but
anyhow let's say four months i think it
may have been
but i want you to now start doing them
with weights so after a period
wrists weights and ankle weights
and they would have to do the
the chemist
i remember setting the task target at
150 non-stop
the chemist
with weights
on the wrists on the ankles
on the last day of uh this particular
students uchidashi
i was waiting in the car for them and i
was quite annoyed because they were late
and in aikido we are very precise
he's
he came to the car pouring with sweat it
was a man came to the car pouring sweat
and i said what are you doing i've been
waiting get in the car we got to go to
the airport
so he got in the car and he just looked
at me and i said what have you been
doing he said who kevin sensei
i said uh how many did you do
he said
200.
well i was staggered from that day to
this i'm staggered that anybody could do
200 of chemis but what staggered me more
was he paused and then said
with weights
so
this would be class to most people as
being superhuman
but it's possible
so from 2014
i decided not to
i moved from greece back to the uk and
decided not to
do any more
dojos not to build any more buy anymore
run anymore i just now teach seminars
and the occasional class in cambridge
the reason i don't want to invest it in
a dojo now it's very time consuming and
costly
but we don't have
the dedicated students and this is what
i'm talking to you out there we don't
have the dedicated students that we did
have then where there would be a regular
supply of uchidashi coming to live with
me and me training them
yes i still get people asked but it's on
very rare occasions
and perhaps several years go by between
being asked
the other thing is a lot of my friends
who run full-time dojos around the globe
are telling me how they're struggling
and without the children's classes they
would have to close the door
so i decided to come up with another
idea and this is where the promotional
side comes in
i decided i've got all these years of
knowledge that was
well i had to spend thousands and
thousands of pounds to get my knowledge
following cytosensing all over the world
narrow scentsy
[Music]
you know i mean i can just go on and on
but
i spent the money to absorb to enhance
my aikido and the information i've got
i want to still
share with others
so i decided when
zoom came along
i can actually
because everybody's living in such a
busy world now they don't perhaps have
the time or want to come to
do a nuccideshe but they are still
the minority of very dedicated students
so through zoom
i have a
a thing called patreon it's a patreon
page
it's where people
pay for different tiers depending on
what their level of
requirement is
there's over
well over a hundred detailed videos
on the patreon site that you can tap
into some yoga some tai chi some
meditation
for those who want to expand further
but on the aikido alone you can see well
over 100
personal detailed
videos and they're
still building
i shall be in the future making podcasts
so
with earphones on or in the car wherever
in the future there'll be podcasts
giving information
so those who are
perhaps in the minority but still want
top tuition
they can have it wherever you are in the
globe
i have students
now that i get a time
zone that suits them
and suits myself
and they put their cameras on and
i correct them i record it and then i
send them the film so they can check
the progress we're making
i'm hoping that we can get people from
beginner all the way to black belt and
perhaps beyond
and so far i'm having a great deal of
success and it's beautiful to watch
their advancement
you know again from a normal human being
who perhaps doesn't have much idea or
those who even think that they do
and we start to polish
and we both get excitement and enjoyment
out of it
so this is to encourage you
to look at my patreon site
see if you want to be part of it
if you want the one-to-one sessions
every month
that's available
it's not a great deal of cost to have
your own
uh one-to-one with me
it's between 15 and 30 minutes once a
month depending on what you want to look
at or what i think you need to learn
i encourage you to consider this if
you're
a true akidoka wishing
to have the finer points in your art
taken
and polished and removed the weaknesses
if you're a determined
person
we will progress together
you can stop at any time you don't sign
up for a period
in the day time you can consider on your
when you're on your own what we've
gained what you've learned
if you can find a partner
you can bring them along and we can
look at techniques together
one of my students in iraq he
lays a carpet down on his lawn and in
between the power
outages we
spend time once a month going through
and polishing
his techniques but we're also polishing
his friends who doesn't pay for the
system
so this was a promotional video
as i say for my patreon site that you'll
find
if you click below the bottom it'll come
up just
tick below they
click below the screen
and it'll come up with my
patreon site go there look see what you
think
we have films
i offer you
a group meeting once a month where we
all discuss
thoughts or techniques
and
you can go for one-to-one tuition if if
you so wish
that the highest tier is for teachers
and
more than students who want me to look
at either their class when they're
teaching
or
their own standard to make allow them to
go higher
i'm a sixth and like a guy i've been
doing as i say like you know for nearly
50 years
i hope i have a lot to offer
and
it's been very enjoyable watching
students grow over my period and i hope
i can help you
advance whatever your level
okay we're all students of our senses
and
thank you for listening
please get in touch if you need more
information by messaging me on my
facebook page or
on this youtube site and i'll get back
to you