welcome to butoh the way of the warrior
podcast this podcast is a collection of
historical and philosophical references
contemplations lectures and exchanges
with David M Valadez his students and
guests podcasts are recorded on the mat
at the sentience Center in Southern
California and in studio these podcasts
are provided to cultivate the warrior on
the way and to add light to their path
questions or comments or observations to
so I always if you remember like the
beginners come and you know I used this
phrase with the beginners a lot you know
power doesn't feel itself when I was
studying in school a lot of people would
talk you know it's very very there's a
lot of cultural capital in the Academy
to be critical of power and they would
focus in on gross examples of power so
tanks coming down the street right and
in my analysis of power because you can
study history from the perspective of
power what I realized through the help
of some key philosophers is that that's
actually the when power is lost there's
a whole other set of power that never
has to use an armored vehicle and that
power is much more dominating
and so in comparison the armored vehicle
to this other kind of power that I'm
talking about is is actually the losing
of power so we all remember when when
the tanks came down Tiananmen Square
right well look where we are now in
China and they're free markets on the
East Coast and then people going all
over the world to study in universities
with this kind of nouveau riche of young
males from millionaire billionaire
business owners now right
I often almost humorously give you that
that moment in Conan the Barbarian
remember so the main bad guy realizes
hey that was I I was all into that
forcing people through violence right
when he's explaining that's not real
power and then he shows this other
example well that's kind of the same
thing you know kind of you know
simplistic almost mythical narrative but
power just should not feel itself
anytime you feel your force your
strength you're not in control you're
not being powerful you're losing power
well you you might when you hear that
you might want to think of this in terms
of a single directional kind of way so
you would say something in your mind as
you understand what I'm saying or you're
listening to what I'm saying you're
thinking that when I push on the skies
because I'm losing power
true but so is the other door
action it's when I push on them that's
making me lose power it's not just I'm
losing power therefore I push on them
and I think that's what happens to your
technique in particular is when you let
them capture your mind like your grip
you feel their you feel the squeeze of
their two hands on your wrist and you
want to pull on it and when you pull on
it well you've now made their grip
stronger versus turn your hand in that
kind of koku inward turning spiral right
and then their grip gets weaker as you
ignore it might we even say it got
weaker because you did ignore it I would
say that's true as well so when I did
when I'm doing the techniques I play a
game like I'm sure not holding on to me
I am huge you're like an ant how many
how many ants did you step on today I
don't know because he's all powerful
compared to the and so when that when
the yuca is grabbing me I just don't
feel them my mind my attention is
somewhere else
kind of like zazen the boat that the
closest it gets to this world is my
posture so in zazen your mind is going
to do mine things right and you can
practice unfetter in it how return to
your posture if you sit there and go oh
my gosh I'm thinking about but I'm going
to need to make dinner tonight we just
added to that thought right your your
mind is like okay wait if I go to Whole
Foods after
I can get I need to get eggs yeah eggs
Oh what am I going to make for dinner
right and then you catch yourself and
then you're like I can't believe I'm
thinking you're still doing it
so the beginner trick is what go back to
your posture nose ears navel hands right
so same thing if my mind comes out of
that void where I don't even know how
many ants I stepped on I don't know who
is holding onto me but if anyone is
holding on to me it just goes to my body
organization hold the shoulder line hold
the hip line hold the pelvic angle find
the ground path you get it but it never
goes to oh my gosh they're holding on to
me I feel how strong they are ah my
wrist because then I will give them
power and I will lose power now let's
not get confused or let's not blow that
out of proportion
it's an aspect of training it's not a
martial element other than my mind can
now be under my control
which is very much a martial element but
I'm not walking around as I'm searching
this building for the active shooter
going I am one with the void I am one
with the void no your mind is constantly
assessing threats right but in your
training especially when you're trying
to work on body organization or done
fettering of the mind or centeredness
mindfulness concentration then you need
to not have your mind go to their grip
not go to their size not go to their
name not go to the rep not go to your
technique do you understand in training
you must do that and then you are
cultivating the mind without it how do
how different are you from what you do
every day before you came to the dojo my
boss yelled at me my mind went there my
wife was cruel to me my kids were asses
to me and my mind goes there right
we were already black belts in that
right so you can look especially in
tonight's training with the emphasis on
cooking whole and body organization you
can rather than trying to do a technique
see if the technique tempts you by
having your mind sync technique that's
that's how I see the training you're
going to do this you're going to do that
and you're gonna do that then I go the
hell I am
I just am because how can I practice
being just em if you don't test me and
tempt me with being something in
particular so as a des you when you get
three techniques you don't think three
techniques you stay no tip you don't you
know you get what I'm saying
so if if you feel like I don't I can't
manage that power all the time I think
okay focus on the other side of that
equation is your mind going towards
their strengths is your mind getting
preoccupied with their presence their
being what they're doing and you're
gonna find yeah every time it's there
every single time I imagine if we were
to if we were to slow down some video
footage of you maybe put some
electrodes on you right before you we
could see on your facial expression some
sort of recognition or frustration with
some sort of weakness that you feel
we're going to see attention of breath
holding a stutter step or something like
that and that's where we see your mind
got stuck on them what they were doing
does this make sense it's not easy but
there's no other way of training it this
is how you train it anything else any
other comments then let me comment on
this so when I started you know everyone
tries to find a market for their martial
art or just for the martial arts in
general you're trying to find some
reason why you should be doing it I hope
you you know like that's kind of a
beginner mistake you don't have a reason
for breathing right you just do it the
more your training is like that the more
you're understanding what the training
is but often times and maybe if you have
kids you even did this you even wanted
this you know they talked about a
confidence the training is good for
confidence we used to have the yellow
pages
right if you didn't know what those are
there was like a phone book and there
would be a ad salesman and they would
come around and put your number do you
want a picture in there we have some
stock footage of some karate guys you're
like well it's not karate oh it's not
maybe you should just make call it
karate anyways because no one knows what
Aikido is right you get that kind of
stuff and then they have you know their
bullets like
we can have a triangle for like a dollar
fifty more you can get a star you know
all this kind of crap and then they
would have these buzzwords confidence
gained confidence it was just a huge
thing and early on I was always like how
does that happen how and why would that
happen from training and you know you
have these can answers and they always
cracked me up because it was always like
well you could you actually know that
you can kick everyone's ass so now
you're confident you know you could it's
just insane who knows that who would
know that I think that's kind of
delusional isn't it it's kind of
romantic you you won the you know one of
the 50th state championships right and
you you now can go anywhere and kick
everyone's ass as so that's why you're
confident it seems stupid to me so the
question remains well how would I is
that even part of what I'm doing and if
it is how would I get it I think
something like confidence is elusive as
power because it first admit it you go
with your intuitive gut reaction power
is when I can push something really hard
but if you think about it that sensation
is more actually that I'm not
all-powerful and the same thing with
this confidence thing if you just think
about it a little bit it does not make
sense right I can't kick everyone's ass
wherever I go
man I'm one delusional bastard
why didn't I just start with the
delusion why spend
99.99 and get my pajama key with my
coupon right why not just I can kick
everyone blows so I think think what is
power
what is it really even go as something
as apparently physical as body
organization what is it
can it really be something so gross and
obvious as shoulder lineman hip
alignment pelvic angle I would say no in
today's class we we had stances but icon
data you could see I don't really need
stances
and I think when you pursue something
deep enough you often come to the
totally opposite answer like this power
one real power doesn't feel itself so if
I feel myself pushing and I overcome
them through my push I'm actually weaker
if I was truly powerful I would never
feel them like all the ants I step on
every day so same thing kind of with
confidence it can't be that I can kick
everyone's ass in the room
it's almost got to be the opposite I
have no need to kick everyone's ass in
the room yeah but can you irrelevant
isn't that going to be where confidence
really is everything is going to be like
that what is center what is center if it
can only be this kind of balance of two
poles maybe it has nothing to do with
poles at all
so as you guys are moving from you know
intermediate to advanced and you're
continuing on because we're doing some
more sophisticated stuff you probably
don't know cuz it always feels the same
right it's always hard it's always
slightly above you you just have to look
back some older videos but I would ask
you to keep in mind as we're doing this
that as wrong as what looking back now
all that material as wrong as that
appears to you now this one's probably
also going to be wrong but you can find
it I think if you just look deep enough
like this power thing right it raises a
lot of issues this question you raised
because if it's a matter that I don't
feel it what do you think most people do
well now I'm just a little fluffy bunny
out there right and and okay your job is
to never let me feel do you see and
that's a kind of artificial cosmetic
right
I mean you grab on and you freaking push
and I don't feel you you get it so we
can't
we can't have this answer and go well
the sensei said it's a matter of not
feeling so I'm never going to write I'm
never going to push through case enter
i'm always i'm the i key i my key
everything that that's a lot as a huge
problem for me in aikido that's why I
tell you you but you're gonna be better
off pushing for a you then you are
for I key you'll find I key when you're
80 but you won't find coke to you if you
start looking for it at 80 so the
technique I think you could ask Taylor
or those who got it if you didn't feel
all that gentle right but to me it does
to me as Nagi felt gentle but to
you is ooh care do you want to hold on
right you want to get off that wild ride
I think that's an important distinction
maybe this idea of the gentle art is
from Nagas perspective and not at all
from Lucas perspective okay let's stop
this concludes this episode of Bhutto
the way of the warrior podcast for more
information please visit sentience
Entercom Sen Shi n cen ter calm or find
us at facebook at sentience enter and on
our youtube channel at section one thank
you for listening