[Music]
right here so if she absorbs it by using
connection same thing goes if it's in
here maybe they start to push
[Music]
so like this don't make and so your body
okay then you have to get over the top
there's no
Stephen you see so he can do it to me I
can do to him we're gonna see it all but
the second I get over the top he has no
[Music]
straight up you see how my finger should
be down that's my greatest mechanical
advantage here no that's this sand up it
doesn't feel comfortable but he could do
it okay I'll know the one try it so make
sure you do the movements fully fingers
[Music]
don't take the target leave it right
there
this map doesn't let her face move back
right and then the throw strike
passenger okay you guys are unconscious
that's my main your unconsciously making
a head
so you're gonna think about okay I'm not
[Music]
concentrating
i mocked it down here and then that's
where my so your consolation is you see
that you want it to go that way so don't
pull it towards you yet
keep it there Oh
around this way have your face back I've
fitted no no no yes it doesn't take much
okay so many remit is about an
unconscious training okay let's go you
don't have to don't get each other but
don't miss don't be unconscious
[Music]
see the hands already
don't do that
Hey
how we want to train that's not deep
training that's shallow lovely okay so
what it would find to do is now let's
clean up some basic forms but the
mistakes were made because they're not
commercials sidetracked by something
else okay
in every level my training is about
concentration your mind is not is not
allowed to want okay do you are there
then we're our mind wander that's why
we're not paying in that's why we can't
change stance that's why we get thrown
over Nidhi
we don't want that we want to read some
mindfulness into the train okay all
right let's try and change from here
wolves now go on going this way if you
see where its head is going so that this
hip goes that's really different than I
going here I do not run there would you
like it's bulls Jim
okay so take advantage of know that
second foot just comes around there's
one error and every time people throw
knees they do this they want to hit and
so they come up and that jeopardizes
your stance because you're you're up on
one leg longer so when you this is this
is immediately where you go okay so when
I have her mapable do you see that and I
have this chin strap and she you move
where you want to see so if she tries to
stand up
bring the head back if she tries to turn
towards me I'm bringing ahead the other
one you see that so you really want
these control points right away then as
I moved that's where her balance good
right so I go back and I'm throwing her
and not find a really not come
higher than that so if you look at my
foot it's about four inches off it's
just here but as a training principle
just to remember the higher your legs
come off the mound takes longer to come
back down and the more precarious your
face is because it's always better to
bring the target down even like I was
trying to do two contradictory things it
won't start on the right so I think
probably at the beginning level we're
having some problems with weight
shifting so the beginner tends to move
the foot before the weight has shifted I
don't mean beginner interpretive senses
I haven't figured that out so what
happens
and then then this will move my Center
and then I'm actually going around my
Center my center moves and gets this new
angle over here and so when you move
your foot versus shift your weight
first you create way more space because
your movement is linear so that will
kind of feel like they're not coming in
they're too far away okay and of course
there's timing but ultimately you have
to have that stickiness which is all
cheap okay because you can if you have
good IP adhesion you can't move them in
as far as you need to you could step the
other way if you wanted to you could
move in but tactically IP really only
need like an extra inch it's not those
forest
so just retire to keep working get that
weight shifting and then I'll always be
on the I on the lookout for adhesion
okay that's Q I don't think we're gonna
get the art right without the occasion
since I'm one of your more recent
podcasts you're talking about this shock
thing that kind of getting over that and
my question was for in that process of
getting exposed to that that repeated
shock and when the strikes come through
how not to let that be a negative
experience so that you're not getting
the positive benefit of it but you're
actually getting worse does that make
sense yes so I I did there's a so the
last podcast I talked about how martial
arts will do some sort of desensitize to
your body and that was part of why I
chose the strikes because James would
not take McKinney when he felt the alien
in his wrist but that's precisely why he
would want to come in because then I
wouldn't be there but so the pain is
motivating you and preventing you from
accessing your wisdom what is new Kimmy
I don't know I can't access it the pain
is telling me forget all that focusing
on that okay that pain in Daniel is no
different from the boxer who can't do
bob and weave because they're blinking
every time the strike comes out of them
right so there's many ways that you are
desensitized and we did we did some
desensitize training here tonight with
the two strikes to your face so that
armor can be king
get used to this but in an earlier
podcast I mentioned that that kind of
training if you are not doing it in the
right kind of environment it can it will
just be abuse
you're basically being treated violently
do you get that so it it begs the
question what is the right kind of
training well it has a lot to do with
you the dish if you if you come to your
training in a very guarded way when I
would in a way that I would ultimately
call non-committed you're holding back
there's aspects of your person of your
life of your culture of your reality
that you just do not put on the table
okay and basically those actions that
action is all about I just have too much
homeostatic energy for my current self
identity
so everything that now you're
experiencing that might cause change is
taking as a threat
it will feel threatening and you will
spark the fight-or-flight response you
will not generate the humility that
another - you might and there's no way
around it if you're if you go well if
you would go more gentle it doesn't work
it's not that's not going to work if you
would go just keep beating me no it
doesn't work either you just turn into a
violent asset so it always comes back to
getting out of our own way right opening
ourselves up exposing ourselves to the
training not leaving things on the table
and I'll go I'll give you this caveat
everyone here might say well that's not
that's I get it I get it when it's
violence upon me but violence is nothing
more than that transgression against
that static homeostatic energy so if you
come into the dojo and you train in a
very guarded way you hold back a lot
anything that is going to threaten that
anything it's gonna feel like a threat
it's gonna actually rub you wrong it
could be four it could be as simple as
so-and-so said this to me it could be as
simple as this teacher that's an allows
aeration on the mat this place all
of that stuff gets threatening
threatening to you and what you're
looking at really is a kind of micro
level of the IP resolution you either
have a chance to put it in play or you
can practice resistance to get that so
the the IPS when we when we first
started people are like this is
killing me what do you mean I gotta make
a school schedule can I just show up
when I want right and then but the
person who's live hey I'm in and I'm
here to train with you and if you say
that helps me I'm gonna go for it and
then everyone learns because we all see
this is a difference between
training to cultivate commitment or
training to maintain a lifestyle of
convenience right and it rubs people
wrong it does there's no difference
right it just does I've had yeah I've
had people who could not keep their IDs
right they're constantly you could tell
us bothering them they always they feel
guilty at first and they get angry at
you this is not an IQ resolution this is
a a trigger event and then you all say
to them hey look you know you can't keep
your IPS we have a two day minimum why
don't you drop down to two days oh my
that's that's it now this
place I'm quitting we're realistic
labels like you can't keep the for days
maybe you can keep the two days that
wasn't the problem the problem was the
resistance the problem is that this is a
different way of being and it's against
how I am right so don't don't worry you
know you're being worked on at all these
levels is just that violence is God's
own little special place because we've
been evolved to not like it but when it
comes to the way our ego words and our
transformative process it's happening
anyways you being rubbed wrong my goal
my my suggestion is if you're going to
be a deshi and this was the point of the
last podcast you don't stop at being
rubbed wrong that is not treated as your
proof
you should do what you want to do that's
where your training is supposed to
happen that is very much like he comes
in and I work I'm here like this you see
this is where I'm supposed to learn do
you get that so those turn of the
signposts that you're supposed to follow
as a deshi in an art of reconciliation
it's supposed to apply to us all on the
map
off the map in martial applications in
daily life in architectural tactical
architectural architectures and in my
relationship to myself okay so don't
wait until you get pounded you can
already tell really
I can already tell the movies not going
to like to be touched in the face dude
it will not like how do you know that
because they're having problems with the
IT s and the minimum training
requirement that the uncommitted which
is I don't want you to to look at it as
a value judgment it's just an equation
the uncommitted is training with
resistance and not to reconcile
resistance and everything
he's operating at that level they just
might not wanted me but they're going
from one conflict to the next conflict
to the next conflict to the next let's
hope this works out for me I hope this
is you know there's always a greener
pasture over there and I open there
there's not supposed to be that you're
supposed to come in and honestly us to
be able to reconcile this energy how not
by changing you look by changing me that
is the principle of light so if you pay
attention I know I I as my training I
will do desensitize training for those
who can take it and then for those who
don't
you might do a week
get all this resistance but they never
feel my technique I don't do my
technique on this it's just gonna start
a cycle of hates me
holy he tried to kill me
he's probably jealous yeah he says I
won't count out here right but I think
you were missing the point when training
operates at that level or not we're
making IKEA something very superficial
something the founder clearly said
should not be back