welcome to boot oh the way of the
warrior podcast this podcast is a
collection of historical and
philosophical references contemplations
lectures and exchanges with David M
Valadez his students and guests podcasts
are recorded on the mat at the sentients
Center in Southern California and in
studio these podcasts are provided to
cultivate the warrior on the way and to
add light to their path
any questions no it does it does but my
is a combination of time and space so
it's not necessarily the case that you
go oh my my UK is shorter arms than my
next to kit and so I need to bring my
t-rex arms out right instead it might be
a matter that you might have to move
earlier or you might get to move later
you don't want to compromise the body
organization because the body
organization is structurally sound
whereas the t-rex arms are not
structurally sound and that's one of the
reasons why you change Lukas because
that's what we mean when we talk about
my where it's not just a concept it's a
skill that you find the right place
right time every single time no matter
who you're with no matter what the
conditions are so the my always changes
but the body organization is the
universal that allows for that change to
cultivate a skill of constant
adaptability or a capacity for
adaptability and yeah it's not you can
think of it too not just in terms of
sizes different UK's have different
energies and they create their own
problems in body organization right
you'll have those those who guess who
you know they just freak you out or
they're freaked out and so they're not
really present and you're going to have
to
learn how to adapt to them well what
does it mean to adapt doesn't mean to do
anything it means take that proper body
organization and find the my for that
you can for that rep and you can go even
further no UK is impossible for any UK
to do the same exact movement every
single time so that would mean that
every single rep that you do you are
practicing that adaptability in fact
that is one of the reasons why the
beginner has such a hard time they don't
have that adaptability they have their
way you see they do it that way no
matter what and so after you get past
you know which foot goes forward how do
you shift your weight that too is
difficult because you won't let go of
your way right you this is how I walk
this is how this is what feels natural
to me and so it takes a while for you to
learn that but let's say after you get
the sequences the steps that you need to
take your your you first have a okay who
you like right you're like this this UK
I can go with and they're just in Europe
we so we say they're in your comfort
zone right you you have matched your
sense of self has coincidentally matched
who they are at that time and they
become your favorite okay that is one
reason why I make you guys change you
know leah has favorite you kid you can't
have favorite again and and why I tell
you guys to go with the people who you
can't stand right those are the ones
that are going to help you learn because
they're not in your comfort zone right
they're not matching you they're making
you uncomfortable why is that it's not
their fault it's your inability to let
go of yourself that is the problem and
you cannot adapt to anything until you
can let go of yourself
so you guys tend to work out together a
lot you're like hey we're both new guys
and we're both big guys you could be
brothers right hey train with other
people go with people that make you feel
like you should have t-rex arms right
they would go with people who who who
can hurt you and all that kind of stuff
right you're gonna be better in the long
run for that and just understand that
natural process - hey this person is
comfortable but structurally get a hold
of that why because you won't let go of
yourself that's not the training that's
the opposite of the train
anything else yes more in the first
drill but like one point I was trying to
follow them it almost felt like they
were moving me the safe just trying to
stay sticky which world were you noggin
so you're not gay
and then you're saying they're trying to
move yeah you're doing this row
I I'm not sure what that means but I if
I use that phrase I think that is closer
to to me as not yet moving them to being
correct
okay often say they're telling you where
to go right because their their movement
is generating the in spaces and so
you're filling the in spaces you're
harmonizing to their young with your yen
and right vice versa so they have to be
telling you where to go
the only limitation to that is when it
comes to these deeper levels of musubi
right it stops making sense then that
they the action-reaction dichotomy isn't
as quite readily usable okay you don't
have that sense like that's what I mean
you have the sense that slow motion in a
drill where you're working on connection
you will develop that sense but when
it's a free-for-all and everyone can do
whatever you won't even remember what
you did let alone that they made you do
it that that connection is really the
only thing that is Marshall when you
have that it doesn't matter what you do
but if you don't have that it also
doesn't matter what you do okay in a
sport environment where the the
opponent's on the other side of the Ring
and a different pair of colored shorts
and there's a ref and then it's okay but
in in the real environment we're
ambushed right and and you always being
on the reactionary side of something if
you can't have that invisible connection
right because you can't see it and we're
not touching it's not it's not I don't
think it's magical at all
I think it's the same senses that you
always use but just like at other levels
grosser levels excuse me the self gets
in the way of my sensory perception
right so what if I could have less self
that gets in the way it would stand a
reason then that those same sense sense
tools would be more perceptive I think
that's what's going on I think we do it
all the time
I think if you ever have been in a love
affair you you do it the problem is that
in the same way with that same lover
that you might have if you're angry or
you feel wrong you can't really hear
what they're telling you you can't
really feel them right well here you are
anything the toxic environment of human
versus human violence and the tendency
is to become more egocentric not less
egocentric and so as I as there is a
relationship between ego centrists
egocentricity and the loss of perception
it would make sense that I cannot see
this thing until a observer would go wow
that thing started way before you
reacted to it you see that but somebody
who could reconcile more of themselves
so they're not so prone to an egocentric
behavior or reaction even in the toxic
admirer
of human versus human violence they
would be able to move right when they
move
it's not magic and you're not reading
the mind you're just present it started
that's all it started that the the the
the difference that we're seeing is on
the other side you starting late it
already happened
that's the difference right
and that kind of that kind of perception
is what we mean is what people try to
get to and they talk about presence
right you're in the present that's the
present the person that's late it's not
in the present
being in the present is the same thing
you you would use for what we want to
call intuition I don't think it is
intuition I think it's just the same old
perception skills not being interfered
with with what we know interferes with
them
so we might call somebody oh he's very
she's very right intuitive that it's
just they're not getting in the way of
what they're observing of what they're
sensing so it could be a dog or a pet
you know a baby or a lover or a child or
a stranger or the victim of a crime or
the reporting party or your boss or
whoever you're not reading minds
you're just not in the way of the
message
so I think
if you want to give some kind of goals
to your training that has to be one of
them you can you can throw out EQ you
can throw out every key on Wazza
that's the goal you need
keep you know eqo Nicole she wanna get
those are all vessels to help you
develop this other skill
but unfortunately they become the
obsession and we forget about the skill
behind them
so you know to me the practic the
question of practicality is not an
architectural one it's a perception one
that's what it is
that kind of training is very difficult
that used to be the only goal of Budo
but now the arts have died they've
become new museum pieces they get
sidetracked with certificates and ranks
and things like that and nobody asked
anymore and you be present show me no
one does that it should be like if you
do one you do one test the instructor
should be able to see did you move right
when they moved or is there a little and
this should be over yes good now go back
get back to work and instead it's like
let's see if you know Nikko and now
let's see if you can do Nikhil from this
attack or that attack and now on to
people really who gives a why does
it stop there
why does it start with two or three or
four or why does it stop with a wrist
grab or a double wrist grab you know why
don't you keep going
it's all misunderstanding so you have to
aim there you have to aim there and the
problem is the problem of self
and the intrusion of cellphone
perception and the warping of time
you
any were helping Virginia when she was
partnered with Taylor and instructing to
go around
yes yeah tie no Hank oh conceptually
because it has DD me 10 Khan right
that's that's why you don't want to
leave the first foot out the first step
right you do EDD me and then you do the
10 Khan so time no Henco is the universe
because it has young and you it has
entering an attorney it has a linear and
and a curve so that you can you can do
that with any technique though because
Aikido is always going to have those
things
yin and yang line and curve and turning
and turning always it's always going to
happen it's representative of
the kind of communion of these
apparent opposites so when you do tie no
Henkel right you will do every technique
right but when you do eat your right
you'll do titanal Henkel right and that
goes the same way because if if I have
my attachment to ego and I have my my
attachment to the other guy there's a
kind of yin-yang there too so I can't
really do tight no hanko until I can be
present until my ego is not pulling me
and blinded me and warping time I can't
you you you can look like it
but just like masters of old look and go
you're doing the movement but it's not
right the timings not there or the
communions not there or it's artificial
it's superficial that's what they're
seeing because there's not
reconciliation of in and out of self and
other that all that can happen in time
no handbook but if you're not doing it
then Titan Ohio is a total waste of time
then so is what everything else
everything else is a waste
or awaiting right a waiting for you to
figure it out
to start trying to figure it out
but like any waiting right it's only
worth the wait if you get it in the end
if we just sit there and wait and we
never get it there's no difference
between waiting and not doing it
I was thinking about about Chang's
question yesterday about you know other
ways of cultivating humility and my
answer was well it could be but it
couldn't you don't have to be it's kind
of the same thing
iki Oh could be the vehicle but it could
also be nothing
because there's something innate about
the human spirit that it can be in one
thing but also be totally absent
that's that's why there's a mystery to
it
I don't think you have to get at the
level of you know the master or the
Buddha to figure that out
about our own humanity
all right everyone's had a cold fish hug
or a cold fish handshake right
or that one kiss that went after you
should have broke up last month right so
clearly you can do a movement and have
it be totally empty
of this deeper invisible intangible but
ever so meaningful stuff that we lumped
together and call spirit
so
how then or why then would Akio be any
different
why then would the art be any different
why then would the dojo be any different
why then with this relationship between
you and me be any different you you make
it what it is either way
and you want to ask how do I put my
spirit in there
I could give you some canned answer but
you know where my mind always goes my
mind always goes to the the the
historical riddle of why subcontinent
India would come up with all this stuff
and would never let go of karma
and reincarnation
and always perplexed me as a student
studying religion and yeah I would you
know you read like the Zen monks and the
they would ask them one one would ask
what he you know master what about
reincarnation hmm it's there but let's
not talk about it that was answer
I think what what what now looking back
I think and I've said it I think what
the Indian philosophers were saying is
like I don't know why
who can say why who can say why one
person can put their whole spirit into
something and another person can do the
same exact movement and have it be void
of spirit really really you really push
anyone that's going to be the answer
I mean you might give hints
you know we're reading that book now I
looked up my what my my critique was I
don't know if any of you guys looked it
up
a short story is this so remember
remember I read it at the very beginning
when it made no sense to me then and the
art of archery I can didn't know what he
was talking about and then later as a
doctoral candidate and a historian and
in the study of religion I came across
this other guy who got to do his you
know post graduate degree on on on that
book which my mentor would never let me
talk about right
so I admit there was kind of like are
you kidding me but the gist of it was
that the author of this thesis was a
kudo practitioner and he basically was
of the mind I I didn't I've never done
Zen I don't do then and and then has
nothing to do with Kudo
well you could say that about anything
couldn't you
you could say that about Aikido look at
Aikido today the founder was deeply
religious you know seriously a mystic
there are more people who aren't even
close to that in Aikido does that mean
that Aikido never had any any influence
at all does that mean like I Iquitos
history stops with you or me and there's
not someone in the future ahead of us
who goes right back to that
my points were you know something like
Kudo like Aikido it's a living history
you don't get to say what it is
certainly not by asking one person
but there's also a history of thought
and there's no way you would have a cue
door in Aikido or anything like that
without a concept pre-existing both the
formation of those two things that made
it possible that you could reach some
sort of spiritual awakening of some kind
some sort of self cultivation through an
entirely otherwise secular practice
that history had to proceed
before you put dough on the end of cue
and in that from the perspective of the
history of thought there is no Kudo
without Zen not possible but is it
possible for anyone do Kudo without
having any connection at all about Zen
even saying that has nothing to do with
it yes because it's a living history so
same thing here you can come to this
dojo even here sit right here across
from me and like I said at the beginning
like can I leave class can I can I
you can do whatever you want haven't you
noticed everyone does
it's kind of cute but is totally true
isn't it
I'm doing whatever I want this is how
this is how I understand the art the art
doesn't make sense to me the other way
I'm not talking about Aikido I'm talking
about my Aikido
even that question what is Aikido that
has a history when people started
talking like that that there was an
Aikido outside of the individual
practitioner there's a history to that
that's not a given
you could go on to define it for
everybody for all times
there's a history there's people who
came up with that idea
and just because I say has nothing to do
with me I'm still influenced by that
history of fun you could read everything
I've ever said or written
as a rebellion against
this universal thing called Aikido
I wouldn't make sense if there wasn't
people doing that
just like the Zen hermit doesn't make
sense if there was no monastery
kind of like the atheist even
right what does Alan Watts say right I'm
an atheist there is no God and I'm his
prophet
like what who
to tests to say there's no God is to be
obsessed with it's like a jilted lover
I'm so over that guy I'm so over him
everyone else is going
right to proclaim atheism is to be
probably the more devout believer than
most believers nowadays
most believers are very inconsistent and
hypocritical but the Atheist is going to
take their atheism everywhere with them
and make sure you know it right
so there's the question okay how do I do
this how do I put my spirit into this
you're not satisfied with my answer
and you probably shouldn't be not at an
individual level
but I would say you know it's probably
more to do with what you won't do versus
what you will do
as a practitioner you'll get further by
looking at what you won't do
I think that's probably why most of the
religions came up with what we moderns
look back as and look his rules an
oppression and why discipline gets this
bad name but I think
they were trying to look at what you
don't do is what counts
because
it lends itself towards consistency
absence of hypocrisy
I think that's also why you have many of
the ancient traditions really making a
problem out of hypocrisy
what what is that not what's going on
when you have one practice that's
supposed to be super meaningful but
you're just going through the motions
yeah
so some of the things we've mentioned
here we know that I need to be brave
let's just take that the warrior virtue
of courage bravery okay all forms of
cowardice
I have to problematize them I have to
observe myself in the face of them and I
have to stop practicing
any form of retreat disengagement
deflection anything like that
then I actually have the virtue of
bravery
disciplined commitment okay all forms of
quitting
I cannot do
I think you'll get more out of these
things by you you will develop the
virtue of commitment not by trying not
you know trying to be committed but by
never quitting
I think that's more doable than telling
ourselves I'm going to really hang in
there
I'm going to keep this diet I'm going to
keep this training schedule
I think you get further by going all
forms acquitting I don't do
all forms of cowardice I don't do
so if I take your question of the virtue
of humility am i opening the door so
that I'm proud of my humility I wouldn't
do that if I go while the virtues
humility but all forms of pride I do not
do
then you can open the doors and they
right it will be an act of service and
self displacement
whereas if you don't you can open the
door and it's actually doing the
opposite
so the same thing in your Aikido what am
I trying to do what is the goal with
each technique
right let's take today don't clash don't
clash all forms of clashing
I will not do
I will not be satisfied with any form of
clashing verses I'm gonna try to blend
how can you do that when you don't know
what that is yet
just you'll feel yourself pushing right
so you know what you should do
hey stop pushing and now guess what
now you're blending
right because every time you try to
blend what do you do instead you do what
you do
I think there's something in the
negative
and I think we don't know how to use it
anymore as a culture because we're
always taught focus on the positive
focus on the positive think positive
you're gonna positive your way into
awakening and then we've never seen that
human history has never shown that
right I imagine now there might be some
religious traditions somewhere that you
know they might have a Anti Ten
Commandment kind of thing is all
positive stuff you know what I mean but
that if you look in the in the in the
spectrum of human history that's like
right right that's the very end like one
line where you had centuries of other
generations ago you know really can't be
that they didn't think of that is
probably it just doesn't work
probably doesn't work
maybe we're missing something when we
about the negative
we're not understanding something
correctly about it and it might be the
teachers that are using it maybe they're
using it incorrectly you see maybe our
problems with those teachers and not
necessarily with this technology
so we're throwing the technology out
because the teacher sucked
many people do that
so I think when you come to your
training okay I don't think the ideals
are beyond any one of you you know
exactly what you're trying to do you
know exactly what you should be doing
but you let yourself do things you
shouldn't be doing
hold yourself true to what you know
that's what we say in the kids class
right do what you know
right little Johnny knows you're not
supposed to run around in the circles
all over whenever you want I don't need
to tell you that
and you know you should not be pushing
into musubi drill
- just hold yourself to it
you know you should be present so don't
let yourself get distracted hold that as
a problem
if need be as a sin bring it up to that
level
so that you can energize yourself from
where you are to where you want to be
this concludes this episode of budeau
the way of the warrior podcast for more
information please visit sentience
Entercom Sen Shi n cen ter comm or find
us at facebook at sentience Center and
on our youtube channel at section one
thank you for listening